alcoholics-anonymous.org 2014-11-09

# Alcoholics Anonymous : Privacy Policy

Thank you for visiting the www.AA.org Web site and reviewing our privacy policy. This policy explains how we handle information about your visit(s) to A.A.’s site, how we protect your privacy and anonymity, and how this site is linked to other sites, such as the A.A.W.S. Online Store and Contributions Online that are internal to Alcoholics Anonymous.

See the Site Disclaimer for information on how you may link from AA.org to outside sites, e.g., local intergroup/central offices or area committees and offices.

**This Privacy Policy was last updated on April 1, 2014.**

**1\. Introduction**

This privacy policy is applicable to this Web site (the **“Site”** ), which is provided and operated by Alcoholics Anonymous World Services, Inc. ( **“A.A.W.S.”** or **“we”** ). **PLEASE READ THE FOLLOWING TERMS CAREFULLY BEFORE USING THE SITE.** Access to the Site is offered to you conditioned on your acceptance without modification of the terms, conditions and notices contained herein (collectively, the “Privacy Policy”). In addition, particular features, applications and activities offered as part of the Site may also be subject to additional privacy terms specified in connection with such features, applications and activities, all of which are incorporated herein by reference.

**BY ACCESSING OR USING THE SITE, YOU AGREE TO THIS PRIVACY POLICY. IF YOU DO NOT AGREE TO THIS PRIVACY POLICY, DO NOT USE THE SITE.**

Please note that this Privacy Policy applies only to information collected via the Site. It does not apply to information that you may submit to us by any other means or to Web sites maintained by other companies.

This Privacy Policy is incorporated into, and part of, A.A.W.S.’s [Terms and Conditions](https://b2c.aaws.org/t-termsandconditions.aspx) ( **“Terms and Conditions”** ) for the A.A.W.S. Online Store, which also govern your use of that related Site. Capitalized terms not defined in this Privacy Policy have the definitions in A.A.W.S.’s Terms and Conditions.

A.A.W.S. may modify, add, or delete portions of this Privacy Policy at any time by posting the changes on this page. Your continued use of the Site after any such changes have been made means you agree to such changes. If A.A.W.S. makes any material changes to the Privacy Policy, it will indicate, at the top of this page, the date the Privacy Policy was last revised.

**2\. Personal Information**

In connection with your use of the Site or particular features or components thereof, you may be required to provide, and we may collect, information that can identify you personally or that can be used with other sources of information to identify you ( **“Personal Information”** ). For example, if you create an account or purchase products on the Site, you will be asked to enter your name, e-mail address, phone number, credit card information and billing address. You may also provide Personal Information when you request customer service or other assistance, sign up to receive emails or other communications for us, or otherwise communicate with us via the Site.

Access to software applications that are owned and operated by third parties ( **“Third-Party Applications”** ) may require you to provide access to your Personal Information to the providers of such Third-Party Applications. In such cases, you will be informed about this either during the registration process, in the terms of use of the Third-Party Application, or in a similar manner. The Third-Party Application provider’s use of your personal information is governed by that third party’s privacy policy. Please note that if you choose to remove a Third-Party Application from your A.A.W.S. account, this does not necessarily mean that the relevant third party provider will delete Personal Information about you that they have previously received. Please visit the privacy policy of the relevant third party to make sure that you understand how they may use the Personal Information you provide to them. If you do not want such use of your Personal Information, you should not register for or use the applicable Third-Party Application.

**3\. Anonymous Information**

When you use the Site, A.A.W.S. may also collect certain information that does not identify you individually ( **“Anonymous Information”** ). For example, A.A.W.S. may collect information about your computer, mobile device, or other device that you use to access the Site (which may include, for example, IP address, geolocation information, unique device identifiers, browser type, browser language, and other transactional information) and about your use of our Web site (which may include, for example, a reading history of the pages you view).

**4\. Use of Cookies**

Like many Web sites, A.A.W.S. may use “cookies,” which are files stored on your computer’s hard drive that help A.A.W.S. identify account holders and optimize their Web site experience. Most browsers accept cookies automatically but allow you to disable them. A.A.W.S. recommends that you leave cookies enabled so it can offer you a better Web site experience. A.A.W.S. will not drop cookies or other tracking devices that are persistent and/or cannot be erased on an end user’s hard drive.

You may occasionally receive cookies from Third-Party Applications. A.A.W.S. does not control these cookies, and these cookies fall outside the scope of this Privacy Policy.

**5\. Our Use of Information**

We use the information we obtain from or about you to help us operate the Site and personalize and improve your experience with the Site and to make certain features, service, activities or functionalities available to you. For example, we may use information we collect (including Personal Information) to:

  * Fulfill orders and complete transactions;
  * Provide you with products and services that you request;
  * Communicate with you about your account, respond to your inquiries and send you information about features and enhancements of the Site;
  * Communicate with you about changes to our policies
  * Send you newsletters and other communications;
  * Optimize or improve our products, services and operations;
  * Detect, investigate, and prevent activities that may violate our policies or be illegal; and
  * Perform statistical, demographic, and marketing analyses of users of the Site and Site usage, including analysis of which content or images users click on or hover over and analysis of which email messages were opened or acted upon when A.A.W.S. sends HTML-formatted email messages (messages resembling Web pages that include graphics).

We may use and store information about you that we receive from other sources to enable us to update and correct the information contained in our database and to better customize your experience with the Site.

**6\. Disclosure of Information**

We will only disclose your Personal Information collected via the Site to other companies and individuals as described in this Privacy Policy.

We may disclose Anonymous Information and any other information that is not Personal Information to other companies and individuals in any manner that A.A.W.S. deems appropriate or necessary.

**Service Providers**

A.A.W.S. occasionally has third-party contractors and agents that provide services to A.A.W.S., such as credit card processing, order fulfillment, marketing, database hosting, web analytics, and providing customer service. These entities may have access to Personal Information in order to perform their functions. We do not authorize them to use the information we share with them for any other purpose.

**Legally Compelled Disclosures**

A.A.W.S. may disclose Personal Information to government authorities, and to other third parties when compelled to do so under law (including under a reasonable interpretation of the law), including, without limitation, in response to court orders and subpoenas.

**Emergency Situations**

A.A.W.S. may disclose Personal Information if required to do so by law or in the good-faith belief that such action is necessary to: (a) conform to applicable law; (b) protect and defend its rights or property, the Site or its Users, and (c) act under emergency circumstances to protect the personal safety of A.A.W.S., its Users, and others.

**Affiliated Entities**

We may disclose Personal Information and other information collected from you to our parent companies, subsidiaries, affiliates and investors.

**Change of Ownership or Corporate Organization**

We may change our ownership or corporate organization. We may transfer Personal Information to another entity in connection with any change of ownership, change of corporate organization or similar transaction, such as, for example, a transfer an entity with which we have merged, that we have acquired or that has acquired A.A.W.S. Under such circumstances A.A.W.S. would use reasonable efforts to require the transferee to follow the practices described in this Privacy Policy, as it may be amended from time to time.

**7\. Security**

We make commercially reasonable efforts to keep your Personal Information secure. We implement a variety of security measures to maintain the safety of your personal information when you place an order or enter, submit, or access your personal information.

We offer the use of a secure server. All supplied sensitive/credit information is transmitted via Secure Socket Layer (“SSL”) technology and then encrypted into our payment gateway provider’s database only to be accessible by those authorized with special access rights to such systems, and are required to keep the information confidential. After a transaction, your credit card information will not be stored on our servers.

No transmission of data over the internet is guaranteed to be completely secure, however. It may be possible for third parties not under the control of A.A.W.S. to intercept or access transmissions or private communications unlawfully, including in the case of your contacting A.A.W.S. by email or a “contact us” or similar feature on the Site. Accordingly, though A.A.W.S. may take reasonable steps to protect the security and integrity of all Personal Information provided to the Site, due to the nature of the internet, A.A.W.S. cannot guarantee that information, during transmission through the internet or while stored on its system or otherwise in its care, will be absolutely safe from intrusion by others, such as hackers. Any such transmission is done at your own risk.

**8\. Children**

This is not a Web site directed to children under the age of 13, and A.A.W.S. does not knowingly collect personal identifiable information from children under 13 years of age. If you are under 13 years of age you should not use this Web site, and under no circumstance should you provide personally identifiable information to A.A.W.S.

**9\. Local Law**

The Site is published in the United States. We make every effort to protect the personal identifiable information of all users of the Site. We attempt to comply with local data protection and consumer rights laws to the extent they may apply to the A.A.W.S. services. If you are uncertain whether this privacy policy conflicts with the applicable local privacy laws where you are located, you should not submit your Personal Information to A.A.W.S.

**10\. Notice to Users Outside of the United States**

If you are located within the European Union, you should be aware that your personal identifiable information will be transferred to the United States of America, the laws of which may be deemed by the European Union to have inadequate data protection. If you are located in a country outside the United States of America and voluntarily submit personal information to us, you thereby consent to the general use of such information as provided in this privacy policy and to the transfer of that information to, and/or storage of that information in, the United States of America.

**11\. Questions?**

If you have any questions about this Privacy policy, please use the Web site **feedback form** to contact us.
